

    Initialize the local directory as a Git repository.

    git init

    Add the files in your new local repository. This stages them for the first commit.

    git add .
    # Adds the files in the local repository and stages them for commit. To unstage a file, use 'git reset HEAD YOUR-FILE'.

    Commit the files that you've staged in your local repository.

    git commit -m 'First commit'
    # Commits the tracked changes and prepares them to be pushed to a remote repository. To remove this commit and modify the file, use 'git reset --soft HEAD~1' and commit and add the file again.

    Copy remote repository URL fieldAt the top of your GitHub repository's Quick Setup page, click 

to copy the remote repository URL.

In the Command prompt, add the URL for the remote repository where your local repository will be pushed.

git remote add origin remote repository URL
# Sets the new remote
git remote -v
# Verifies the new remote URL

Push the changes in your local repository to GitHub.

git push origin master
# Pushes the changes in your local repository up to the remote repository you specified as the origin

